var quiz = {
  easy: [{
          "question": "In the movie  'Despicable Me', what is the name of Gru's friend and assistant?",
          "choices": ["Dr. Fenario", "Dr. Renario", "Dr. Nefario"],
          "correct": "Dr. Nefario"
        }, {
          "question": "In the animated movie 'Big Hero 6' what is the name of the inflatable robot?",
          "choices": ["Baymax", "GoGo", "GoGo"],
          "correct": "Baymax"
        }, {
          "question": "Mixing blue and yellow produces which colour?",
          "choices": ["Green", "Purple", "Brown"],
          "correct": "Green"
        }, {
          "question": "A female goat is called a ... ?",
          "choices": ["Mare", "Doe", "Ewe"],
          "correct": "Doe"
        }, {
          "question": "The process of water moving through a plant is called?",
          "choices": ["Filtration", "Transpiration", "Evaportation"],
          "correct": "Transpiration"
        }, {
          "question": "Which is the correct spelling of the capital city of Russia?",
          "choices": ["Mosko", "Moscow", "Mosscoe"],
          "correct": "Moscow"
        }, {
          "question": "What is the number in sequence? 1,4,8,13,19,?",
          "choices": ["26", "27", "28"],
          "correct": "26" 
        }, {
          "question": "Around 15% of the world's population speaks Mandarin which makes it our most common language. Which is our second most common language?",
          "choices": ["Spanish", "English", "Hindi"],
          "correct": "Spanish" 
        }, {
          "question": "In which year was the first iPad released? (IPAD not IPOD).",
          "choices": ["2006", "2008", "2010"],
          "correct": "2010" 
        }, {
          "question": "The brown recluse spider is also known as the ...?",
          "choices": ["Violin Spider", "Guitar Spider", "Trumpet Spider"],
          "correct": "Violin Spider" 
        },{
          "question": "Most moles have an extra 'thumb' to help with digging.",
          "choices": ["TRUE", "FALSE"],
          "correct": "TRUE" 
        },  {
          "question": "Who is the founder of Microsoft?",
          "choices": ["Bill Gates", "Steve Jobs", "Steve Wozniak"],
          "correct": "Bill Gates"
        }, {
          "question": "1 byte = ?",
          "choices": ["8 bits", "64 bits", "1024 bits"],
          "correct": "8 bits"
        }, {
          "question": "The C programming language was developed by?",
          "choices": ["Brendan Eich", "Dennis Ritchie", "Guido van Rossum"],
          "correct": "Dennis Ritchie"
        }, {
          "question": "The distance from the centre of a circle to any point on that circle is the ..?",
          "choices": ["Circumference", "Diameter", "Radius"],
          "correct": "Radius" 
        }],
moderate: [{
          "question": "The word 'mosquito' is from the Portuguese or  Spanish for ...?",
          "choices": ["little fly", "annoying fly", "biting fly"],
          "correct": "little fly"
        }, {
          "question": "How many moons does Jupiter have?",
          "choices": ["7", "37", "67"],
          "correct": "67"
        }, {
          "question": "We use SD Cards for storing digital data. What does SD stands for?",
          "choices": ["Standard Digital", "Secure Digital", "Storage Device"],
          "correct": "Secure Digital"
        }, {
          "question": "If you are panivorous, what forms most of your daily diet?",
          "choices": ["Fruit", "Bread", "Soup"],
          "correct": "Bread"
        }, {
          "question": "Blackbeard was a famous pirate in the early 1700s. What was his real name?",
          "choices": ["Bernard Twist", "Edgar Theaton", "Edward Teach"],
          "correct": "Edward Teach"
        }, {
          "question": "What type of animal has the common name of 'waxy monkey'?",
          "choices": ["Frog", "Snake", "Snail"],
          "correct": "Frog"
        }, {
          "question": "Which is the strongest biological material ever discovered in the natural world?",
          "choices": ["limpets teeth", "Spider silk", "lions claw"],
          "correct": "limpets teeth"
        }, {
          "question": "Where would you find a cricket's ears?",
          "choices": ["On its head", "On its wings", "On its legs"],
          "correct": "On its legs"
        }, {
          "question": "The word 'clue' comes from a much older word 'clew' which referred to ...?",
          "choices": ["a ball of thread or yarn", "a bale of hay or straw", "a boot or shoe"],
          "correct": "a ball of thread or yarn"
        }, {
          "question": "UNICEF is a United Nations organization that helps ...?",
          "choices": ["the environment", "science", "children"],
          "correct": "children"
        }, {
          "question": "There was no official national anthem for the USA until which year?",
          "choices": ["1901", "1931", "1935"],
          "correct": "1931"
        }, {
          "question": "Approximately how many tons of hydrogen does the sun consume every second?",
          "choices": ["6 tons", "6000 tons", "600 million tons"],
          "correct": "600 million tons"
        }, {
          "question": "In which season do we need to more fat?",
          "choices": ["Rainy season", "Summer", "Winter"],
          "correct": "Winter"
        }, {
          "question": "How many teeth does a normal dog have?",
          "choices": ["34", "38", "42"],
          "correct": "42"
        }, {
          "question": "If speed of rotation of the earth increases, weight of the body ..",
          "choices": ["increases", "remains unchanged", "decreases"],
          "correct": "decreases"
        }],
  hard: [{
          "question": "Tanya is older than Eric, Cliff is older than Tanya. Eric is older than Cliff. If the first two statements are true, the third statement is",
          "choices": ["true", "false", "Iuncertain"],
          "correct": "false"
        }, {
          "question": "Blueberries cost more than strawberries. Blueberries cost less than raspberries. Raspberries cost more than strawberries and blueberries. If the first two statements are true, the third statement is",
          "choices": ["true", "false", "uncertain"],
          "correct": "true"
        }, {
          "question": "All the trees in the park are flowering trees. Some of the trees in the park are dogwoods. All dogwoods in the park are flowering trees. If the first two statements are true, the third statement is",
          "choices": ["true", "false", "uncertain"],
          "correct": "true"
        }, {
          "question": "Mara runs faster than Gail. Lily runs faster than Mara. Gail runs faster than Lily. If the first two statements are true, the third statement is",
          "choices": ["true", "false", "uncertain"],
          "correct": "false"
        }, {
          "question": "Apartments in the Riverdale Manor cost less than apartments in The Gaslight Commons. Apartments in the Livingston Gate cost more than apartments in the The Gaslight Commons. Of the three apartment buildings, the Livingston Gate costs the most. If the first two statements are true, the third statement is",
          "choices": ["true", "false", "uncertain"],
          "correct": "true"
        }, {
          "question": "Class A has a higher enrollment than Class B. Class C has a lower enrollment than Class B. Class A has a lower enrollment than Class C. If the first two statements are true, the third statement is",
          "choices": ["true", "false", "uncertain"],
          "correct": "false"
        }, {
          "question": "Four people witnessed a mugging. Each gave a different description of the mugger. Which description is probably right?",
          "choices": ["He was average height, thin, and middle-aged", "He was tall, thin, and middle-aged", "He was tall, thin, and young"],
          "correct": "He was tall, thin, and middle-aged"
        }, {
          "question": "Ms. Forest likes to let her students choose who their partners will be; however, no pair of students may work together more than seven class periods in a row. Adam and Baxter have studied together seven class periods in a row. Carter and Dennis have worked together three class periods in a row. Carter does not want to work with Adam. Who should be assigned to work with Baxter?",
          "choices": ["Carter", "Adam", "Dennis"],
          "correct": "Carter"
        }, {
          "question": "At the baseball game, Henry was sitting in seat 253. Marla was sitting to the right of Henry in seat 254. In the seat to the left of Henry was George. Inez was sitting to the left of George. Which seat is Inez sitting in?",
          "choices": ["251", "255", "256"],
          "correct": "251"
        }, {
          "question": "As they prepare for the state championships, one gymnast must be moved from the Level 2 team to the Level 1 team. The coaches will move the gymnast who has won the biggest prize and who has the most experience. In the last competition, Roberta won a bronze medal and has competed seven times before. Jamie has won a silver medal and has competed fewer times than Roberta. Beth has won a higher medal than Jamie and has competed more times than Roberta. Michele has won a bronze medal, and it is her third time competing. Who will be moved to the Level 1 team?",
          "choices": ["Roberta", "Beth", "Michele"],
          "correct": "Beth"
        }, {
          "question": "Four friends in the sixth grade were sharing a pizza. They decided that the oldest friend would get the extra piece. Randy is two months older than Greg, who is three months younger than Ned. Kent is one month older than Greg. Who should get the extra piece of pizza?",
          "choices": ["Randy", "Greg", "Ned"],
          "correct": "Ned"
        }, {
          "question": "The high school math department needs to appoint a new chairperson, which will be based on seniority. Ms. West has less seniority than Mr. Temple, but more than Ms. Brody. Mr. Rhodes has more seniority than Ms. West, but less than Mr. Temple. Mr. Temple doesn't want the job. Who will be the new math department chairperson?",
          "choices": ["Mr. Rhodes", "Mr. Temple", "Ms.West"],
          "correct": "Mr. Rhodes"
        }, {
          "question": "Danielle has been visiting friends in Ridge-wood for the past two weeks. She is leaving tomorrow morning and her flight is very early. Most of her friends live fairly close to the airport. Madison lives ten miles away. Frances lives five miles away, Samantha, seven miles. Alexis is farther away than Frances, but closer than Samantha. Approximately how far away from the airport is Alexis?",
          "choices": ["nine miles", "eight miles", "six miles"],
          "correct": "six miles"
        }, {
          "question": "Nurse Kemp has worked more night shifts in a row than Nurse Rogers, who has worked five. Nurse Miller has worked fifteen night shifts in a row, more than Nurses Kemp and Rogers combined. Nurse Calvin has worked eight night shifts in a row, less than Nurse Kemp. How many night shifts in a row has Nurse Kemp worked?",
          "choices": ["eight", "nine", "ten"],
          "correct": "nine"
        }, {
          "question": "Children are in pursuit of a dog whose leash has broken. James is directly behind the dog. Ruby is behind James. Rachel is behind Ruby. Max is ahead of the dog walking down the street in the opposite direction. As the children and dog pass, Max turns around and joins the pursuit. He runs in behind Ruby. James runs faster and is alongside the dog on the left. Ruby runs faster and is alongside the dog on the right. Which child is directly behind the dog?",
          "choices": ["Rachel", "Ruby", "Max"],
          "correct": "Max"
        }],
};
var score = {
  easy:0,
  moderate:0,
  hard:0
};

var level = {
  easy:0,
  moderate:0,
  hard: 0
};

// define elements
var content = $("content"),
  questionContainer = $("question"),
  choicesContainer = $("choices"),
  scoreContainer = $("score"),
  submitBtn = $("submit");

// init vars
var currentQuestion = 0,
  askingQuestion = true;

var diff;
var choices;
var choicesHtml;


    
function $(id) { // shortcut for document.getElementById
  return document.getElementById(id);
}

function askQuestion() {
  
  console.log("inside askquestion");
  choices = quiz[diff][currentQuestion].choices;
  // console.log(choices);
  choicesHtml = "";
 // set level value to 1
 if (quiz[diff]) {

 }
  // loop through choices, and create radio buttons
  for (var i = 0; i < choices.length; i++) {
    choicesHtml += "<span class='col-lg-12 col-xs-12 choizis'><input type='radio' name='quiz" + currentQuestion +
      "' id='choice" + (i + 1) +
      "' value='" + choices[i] + "'>" +
      " <label for='choice" + (i + 1) + "'>" + choices[i] + "</label></span><br><br>";

  }
  console.log('quizlength '+ quiz[diff].length);
  console.log('question ' + currentQuestion);
  // load the question
  questionContainer.textContent = 
    quiz[diff][currentQuestion].question;

  // load the choices
  choicesContainer.innerHTML = choicesHtml;

  // setup for the first time
  if (currentQuestion === 0) {
    scoreContainer.textContent = "Score: 0 right answers out of " +
      quiz[diff].length + " possible.";
    scoreContainer.textContent = "NOTE:Leaving question will be no points";
    submitBtn.textContent = "Submit Answer";
  }
}

function checkAnswer() {
  console.log('inside check answer');
  // are we asking a question, or proceeding to next question?
  if (askingQuestion) {
    submitBtn.textContent = "Next Question";
    askingQuestion = false;

    // determine which radio button they clicked
    var userpick,
      correctIndex,
      radios = document.getElementsByName("quiz" + currentQuestion);
    for (var i = 0; i < radios.length; i++) {
      if (radios[i].checked) { // if this radio button is checked
        userpick = radios[i].value;
      }

      // get index of correct answer
      if (radios[i].value == quiz[diff][currentQuestion].correct) {
        correctIndex = i;
      }
    }

    // setup if they got it right, or wrong
    var labelStyle = document.getElementsByTagName("label")[correctIndex].style;
    labelStyle.fontWeight = "bold";
    if (userpick == quiz[diff][currentQuestion].correct) {
      score[diff]++;
      // labelStyle.color = "green";
    }
    //  else {
    //   labelStyle.color = "white";
    // }
    scoreContainer.textContent = "Score: 0 right answers out of " +
      quiz[diff].length + " possible.";
    scoreContainer.textContent = "NOTE:Leaving question will be no points";
  } else { // move to next question
    // setting up so user can ask a question
    askingQuestion = true;
    // change button text back to "Submit Answer"
    submitBtn.textContent = "Submit Answer";
    // if we're not on last question, increase question number
    console.log(quiz[diff].length - 1);
    if (currentQuestion < quiz[diff].length - 1) {
      currentQuestion++;
      askQuestion();
    } else {
      if(level.easy == 1 && level.hard == 1 && level.moderate == 1){
        GetResults();
      }else{
        // choose difficulty //change
        Presults();
      }
    }


  }
}

function Presults(){
  if (currentQuestion == 14) {
    $('#div_Q').hide();
    $('#content').show();
  }
  content.innerHTML = "<h2>You've completed the quiz!</h2>" +
    "<h2>" + score[diff] + " out of " + quiz[diff].length + " questions, " +
    Math.round(score[diff] / quiz[diff].length * 100) + "%<h2>" +
     "<button class='get'>Choose difficulty</button>";
}
function GetResults() {

  content.innerHTML = "<h2>You've completed the quiz!</h2>" +
    "<h2>" + score + " out of " + quiz[diff].length + " questions, " +
    Math.round(score / 45 * 100) + "%<h2>" +
     "<button class='get'>Choose Again HELLLLOOOOOOOOOOOOO!</button>";
}
// window.addEventListener("load", askQuestion, false);
submitBtn.addEventListener("click", checkAnswer, false);
